(DOOR BUZZING)
Packer.
Packer
Yes, sir.
在,先生
- Have you discovered where the Professor is?
- Yes, Mr Vaughn.
- 你发现教授在哪里了吗？  - 是的, Vaughn 先生
Go and collect him.
去把他弄回来
I want work started on the production
of the machines immediately.
我期望机器的生产工作可以立即开始
Go and recapture Watkins.
去把 Watkins 重新抓回来
Don't let anything or anyone stop you.
不要让任何事、任何人阻止你
- Oh, thanks!  - Thank goodness you made it.
- 哦, 谢谢！  - 感谢老天你搞定了
- Any trouble?  - Hundreds of Cybermen about, sir.
- 有问题吗？  - 周围有百多个赛博人, 长官
The sooner we get out of here, the better.
Everybody ready?
我们越早离开这里越好, 都准备好了吗？
- ALL: Yes!
- ISOBEL: Yes, we're ready, we're coming.
- 准备好了!  - 是的, 我们准备好了, 我们来了
Listen!
听！
(TYRES SCREECHING)
We'd better get out of here,
out of the back way as quickly as possible.
我们最好离开这里, 尽快离开这后面fixme
- Right!  - Come on, move, everybody. Quickly!
- 好！  - 快点, 动起来, 所有人, 快！
Out of the back door. Hurry it up.
从后门出去, 快起来
Come on, Jamie. Professor, all right? Good.
快点, Jamie．教授, 没事吧？ 好
(GUN FIRING)
- Yes, Jimmy, where are you?
- TURNER: In bother, sir. We need help.
- 是的, Jimmy, 你在哪里？  - 遇到麻烦了, 先生, 我们需要帮助
- Can you give us a chopper?
- Yes.
- 你能给我们派一架直升机吗？  - 可以
- Can you make sector five?
- We can try, sir.
- 你们赶到第五区吗？  - 我们可以试试, 先生
Right, I'll get the chopper there. Out.
好, 我让直升机去那里, 挂了
How could they escape the Cyber-control?
他们怎么能摆脱赛博控制？
It's that Doctor, something to do with him.
是那个博士, 跟他有点关系
You should've got rid of him
when you had the chance.
你有机会的时候应该干掉他的
Shut up, Packer!
闭嘴, Packer!
I must go on with the invasion.
我必须去继续推进入侵的事情
But what about the Professor?
要教授怎么处理？
Without him, we can't make any more machines.
Without machines, we can't control the Cybermen.
没有他, 我们制造不了任何机器．没有机器, 我们控制不了赛博人
Let me worry about that.
让我来操心这个事吧
For the moment,
I have the Cybermen exactly where I want them.
现在这个时候, 赛博人正在我期望它们所在的位置fixme
Yeah, but for how long?
是, 但会持续多久？
Now, can you honestly say
that everything's going according to plan?
现在, 你能否实话告诉我, 是不是所有事情都会按计划走？
That nothing's been overlooked? Well, can you?
没有漏掉什么吧？怎样, 能吗？
Just obey my orders!
服从我的命令就是了！
Now, get in touch with the compound
and have the radio beam projected.
现在, 联系工业园, 将无线电信号发送出去
The invasion fleet must be brought in.
必须得把入侵的舰队带进来
Now, Doctor, we must deal with
this invasion you say is coming.
现在, 博士, 你所说的即将来临的这场入侵, 我们必须对付它
Yes, at least we know where they'll land.
是的, 至少我们知道他们会在那里着陆
They'll home in on Vaughn's radio signal.
它们会沿着 Vaughn 的无线电讯号过来
Would we be able to pick them off
with anti-missile missiles?
我们能够用反导导弹拦到它们吗？
Yes, that's a good idea. We might have a try.
嗯, 这是一个好主意．我们可以试一试
Right. There's a base near Henlow Downs.
Er, just a minute.
好, 在 Henlow Downs 附近有一个基地．呃, 等一下
- Sergeant Walters?
- Oh, Zoe, sit down, dear. It's a bit bumpy.
- Walters 中士吗？  - 噢, Zoe, 坐下, 有一点颠簸
- Now, how's Jamie's leg?
- Oh, it's just a slight flesh wound.
- 现在 Jamie 的脚怎样了？  - 哦, 只是有点轻微的皮外伤
But he's furious, because the Army doctor
won't let him walk on it.
但他吵得厉害, 因为军队医生不让他走路
Well, he would be, wouldn't he?
How's the Professor?
啊, 他会的, 对吧？教授怎样？
Oh, he'll be all right. Isobel's with him.
噢, 他会没事的．Isobel 在陪着他
(DOCTOR SIGHS)
- Anything I can do, Doctor?  - Well, I...
- 我能做点什么吗, 博士？  - 唔, 我...
I suggest that you...you go with the Brigadier.
我建议你...你跟准将走
As much as I detest computers, I...
鉴于我如此讨厌电脑, 我...
I think that remarkable brain of yours
will come in very handy.
我觉得你那聪明的脑袋瓜会带来很多便利
Right. What are you going to do?
好．你打算做什么？
I think it's about time I had a serious talk
with our Mr Vaughn.
我觉得是时候去跟我们的 Vaughn 先生进行一次严肃的谈话了
What, go back?
But he'd kill you as soon as look at you.
什么, 又回去？但他会一看见你就杀了你的
No, we need time
if we're going to stop this attack,
不, 我们需要时间, 如果我们想要阻止这场攻击的话
and I think I can get us that time.
而我觉得我可以帮我们争取到那些时间
No, this is madness.
I can't afford to let you take that risk.
不, 这太疯狂了．让你去冒险, 我承担不起这责
You can't afford not to, Brigadier.
不让我去的花, 你也承担不起, 准将
If you're going to attack
the Cybermen with missiles,
如果你打算用导弹攻击这些赛博人
they're going to retaliate,
and we want to know how and with what.
他们会反击, 我们需要知道用什么方式、什么手段
But how can you find that out?
但你怎么能搞到那些信息？
I'll leave my radio on and then you'll hear
every word that passes between me and Vaughn.
我会把无线电开着, 你们会听到我和 Vaughn 说的每一个字
But you'll never get near the place.
The whole area will be crawling with Cybermen.
但你不能靠近那个地方, 那里将会挤满了赛博人
Oh, there's one place
where there'll be no Cybermen.
哦, 有一个地方不会有赛博人
- Where's that?  - In the sewers.
- 那里？  - 下水道里
UNIT Control. This is the Doctor.
UNIT 控制中心, 我是博士
- Is Brigadier there, please?
- WALTERS: Hold on a moment, sir, I'll get him.
- 准将在吗, 请问？  - 等一下, 先生, 我去叫他
(STATIC BUZZING)
BRIGADIER: Yes, Doctor, go ahead.
在, 博士, 请说
Er, Brigadier, I've just entered the sewers.
呃, 准将, 我刚刚进入了下水道
I'm going to make my way to Vaughn's headquarters.
正要前往 Vaughn 的总部
I'll give you a call when I get there.
等我到了那里我会呼你
Right. We'll have a chopper in the area
好, 我们会安排一架直升机守那个区域/?
- in case you get in trouble.
- Thank you.
- 以防你万一遇到麻烦  - 谢谢你
(WATER DRIPPING)
And all the main communication centres
are now manned by our forces?
所有的通讯中心都已经被我们的人控制了吧？
Yes, but, um...
是的, 但是, 呃...
What? But what, Packer?
怎么了, 但是什么, Packer?
Well, we can't make a complete takeover
without a full invasion force.
只是, 没有一支完整的入侵队伍的话, 我们不能完全接管
They'll arrive, Packer, they'll arrive.
它们会到的, Packer, 它们会到的
And when they do,
等他们到了
there won't be one city in the entire world
that we don't control.
整个世界没有一个城市我们掌控不了
Think of it, Packer, the entire world!
想想吧, Packer, 整个世界！
(ALARM SOUNDING)
It's the security alarm,
the UNIT forces must have...
是安全警报, UNIT 队伍肯定已经...
Packer.
Packer
There you are.
是你啊fixme
I hope I haven't called
at an inconvenient moment, but I...
我期望我来访的时间没有给你带来不便, 但是我...
I would rather like a word with you.
我想要跟你说两句话
Clever of you to avoid our Cyber-control beam.
你很聪明, 想要躲开赛博控制波
Oh, it was nothing.
噢, 那没什么
I'll...I'll come up, I know the way.
我...我现在上来, 我知道路
He must be out of his mind!
他肯定是失心疯了
Far from it, Packer.
远远不是, Packer
Have the guards search the building,
just in case he's brought any friends with him.
让警卫们搜索整栋大楼, 以防他带了一些朋友过来
Tell the raiding party to stand by.
告诉突袭小组做好准备
- Yes, sir.
- DOCTOR: (WHISPERING) Ah, Brigadier. Brigadier.
- 是, 长官  - 啊, 准将, 准将
- Yes, Doctor, go ahead.
- I am just about to enter the lion's den.
- 收到, 博士, 请说  - 我就要进入虎穴了
I will leave the radio on as of now.
从现在开始我会让无线电一直开着
- Right. Good luck.  - Thank you.
- 好, 祝你好运  - 谢谢
Keep that channel open
and get the whole thing on tape.
一直开着那个频道, 把整个过程录下来
- Yes, sir.  - If he yells for help while I'm away,
- 是, 长官  - 如果他呼救, 而我有不在
- send in everything we've got to get him out.
- Right.
- 把我们所有的人派进去救他出来  - 好的
VAUGHN: Ah, Doctor, what an unexpected pleasure.
啊, 博士, 真是不胜荣幸啊
Do come in.
请进来
And you trust them?
你信任它们吗？
Doctor, I've worked with the Cybermen
for five years, preparing this invasion.
博士, 我同赛博人合作了五年, 共同准备这次入侵
I know them, the way they think,
the single-mindedness of their purpose.
我了解它们, 它们的思维方式, 他们试图创造单一思想fixme
Then you must know what ruthless
and inhuman killers they are.
那你肯定知道它们都是冷血无情的杀手吧
Of course.
当然
But then, they are my allies, not my enemies.
但是呢, 它们时候我的同盟, 不是我的敌人
Do you really think they'll honour
any bargain that you make with them?
你真的觉得它们会遵循你同他们谈好的交易？
Oh, I've planned this whole operation in great detail,
allowing for every possible factor.
噢, 我策划了这整个行动, 事无巨细, 考虑了各种因素
It was I who contacted them in deep space,
当初是我联系了深空中的它们
provided the means by which they travelled to Earth.
给它们提供了到达地球的手段
And masterminded the whole operation from A to Z.
从 A 到 Z 策划了这次行动的整个过程
(SCOFFS)
They have merely provided their advanced
scientific skills, their might and strength.
它们只不过是提供了它们的先进科技, 和一点力气
And what do they get out of all this?
那它们能从这里面得到什么呢？
What they want and what they're going to get
are two entirely different things.
它们想要什么和它们会得到什么, 是两件完全不同的事
Oh, you're a fool, Vaughn.
噢, 你是个傻瓜, Vaughn
When they get here, they'll take over.
一旦它们到了这里, 它们就会全夺走
All Cybermen here are conditioned to obey my orders.
根据条件, 所有赛博人都要服从我的命令
They are directly under my command.
它们都受我直接指挥
Oh, possibly. But what about the others,
out there in space?
噢, 有可能．但另外那些呢, 在太空里的那些？
Are they conditioned to obey your commands?
按条件它们也会服从你的指挥？
If they're not, I'll destroy them.
如果它们不服从, 我会消灭他们
- With the Professor's machine?  - Yes.
- 就用教授的机器？  - 是的
With one machine?
就凭一台机器？
I'll have more made.
我会安排批量制造
But you'll have to have
the Professor's help to do that, won't you?
但你得需要教授的帮助才能这样做, 对吧？
We've got the Professor.
教授在我们手上
They'll be under my command,
exactly like the others.
它们会听我指挥的, 跟其它的完全一样
But you can't be sure of that, can you?
但对此你不能确定, 对吧？
(ELECTRONIC SIGNAL PULSATING)
Well, we can't get them all.
Let's take as many as we can.
好吧, 我们不能全干掉它们, 也要能搞定多少就搞定多少
- Lift off the activation check.
- Coordinate programme running, sir.
- 开始激活检查  - 协同程序已经开始运行, 长官
- Link programme to telemeter guidance.
- PETERS: Roger.
- 将程序连接到测距导航仪  - 收到
Major, I think we stand a good chance of
getting at least 90 percent of them.
少校, 我觉得我们有很大可能可以消灭它们的９成
- How? We haven't got enough missiles.
- Oh, please, Major.
- 怎么弄？我们没有足够的导弹  - 哦, 拜托, 少校
Just knocking out half a dozen of them
will do very little good at all.
只是敲掉它们中的一部分的花, 完全没有多大收益
Let's try for them all.
我们得尽力把它们全搞定
Look, miss, I know my business and
I'm telling you we haven't got enough missiles.
听着, 小姐, 我知道我的情况, 我告诉你我们没有足够的导弹
Yes, you have.
有, 你有
These things are coming in in a formation pattern.
这些家伙已经以编队形式过来了
Now if you set your missiles carefully,
you can set up a chain reaction of explosions.
现在如果你们仔细设定你们的导弹, 就可以引发链式爆炸
No, there isn't time to compute
all the relevant information.
不行, 没有足够的时间来计算所有相关的因素了
- They'd be on top of us by then.
- Give me 30 seconds.
- 到时候它们已经到我们头上了  - 给我３０秒
Give her what she asks, Major. 30 seconds.
她要就给她吧, 少校, ３０ 秒
- But, sir, this is ridiculous!
- Just 30 seconds.
- 但是, 长官, 这完全不可能啊！  - 就３０秒
- Hold for 30 seconds!
- Sir, that doesn't give us much time.
- 稳住３０秒  - 长官, 给我们的时间不多了
All right, Sergeant, I know.
Countdown to begin at T minus 45 seconds.
好了, 中士, 我知道．开始４５秒倒计时
Here. Feed this into your computer.
给, 把这个输入到你们电脑里面去
Do as she says. Now. I'll take over.
按她说的做．现在, 我来接管
Sir.
长官
- You'd better be right.  - I am.
- 你最好是对的  - 我当然是
T minus 45 seconds from...now.
４５秒倒计时...开始
(WHIRRING)
Once the Cybermen take over,
they'll destroy the Earth as we know it!
一旦赛博人占领这里, 它们会毁灭地球的, 我们都知道！
You're just playing for time, aren't you?
你只是在拖延时间, 对吗？
I'm trying to stop you
from destroying the human race!
我是在尽力阻止你毁灭整个人类种族！
Your UNIT friends...
你那些 UNIT 的朋友...
You presumably managed to protect them
from the Cyber-control as well?
估计你肯定设法保护了他们, 不让他们受到赛博控制波影响？
What are they planning?
他们在谋划些什么？
I don't know what you're talking about.
我不知道你在说些什么
Packer?
Yes, sir.
在, 先生
- Is the radio beam in the compound aligned yet?
- Yes, sir, it's all ready.
- 工业园的无线电波已经调校好了么？  - 是的, 先生, 都准备好了
Good. Then link the beam to the invasion fleet.
好, 那把它跟入侵舰队的讯号连接起来
Right, Mr Vaughn.
好的, Vaughn 先生
Now whatever it is
your UNIT friends are trying to do...
现在, 不管你在 UNIT 的朋友打算做什么...
it's too late.
都来不及了
COMMUNICATOR: The first transporter fleet
is being attacked and destroyed.
第一支传送舰队已经被击中, 都毁灭了
- You have betrayed us.  - No!
- 你背叛了我们  - 没有！
The failure of this mission is due to you.
这次任务的失败都是因为你
We will now take over the invasion.
我们现在要接管入侵行动
No! Wait! Give me time!
不, 等等！给我点时间！
I can stop this opposition!
我可以组织那些抵抗者！
There is no more time.
不会有更多时间了
We no longer need you.
我们不再需要你了
The Cyber-Megatron bomb will be delivered.
赛博超级炸弹已经发送
We must destroy life on Earth completely.
我们必须完全摧毁地球上的生命
Every living being.
所有活着的生物